<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yogesh Dhimate</title>
    <link>https://www.dhimate.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yogesh Dhimate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhimate.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/about/</guid>
      <description> I’m Yogesh Dhimate. This is my personal website. All opinions expressed here are my own.
Find me here  LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhimate/ GitHub : https://www.github.com/dhimate  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Extensive global consulting, management and leadership experience in various roles as solutions manager, solutions architect and people leader in the software industry. Deep experience in enterprise solutions using message-oriented middleware, enterprise service bus, on premise/cloud/hybrid implementation and API based architecture. Adept in analyzing information system needs, evaluating end-user requirements, custom designing solutions for complex information systems. Effective in work situations requiring an ability to manage concurrent projects and responsibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/books/</guid>
      <description>I am currently reading - Linchpin : Are You Indispensible by Seth Godin
2021  Linchpin : Are You Indispensible - Seth Godin (Jan 2021)  2020  Range: Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World - David Epstein (Dec 2020) Made to Stick - Dan Heath and Chip Heath (Dec 2020) Atomic Habits - James Clear (Nov 2020) Back Home: An Emotional Guide for NRIs Who Are on the Fence - Nupur Dave (Nov 2020) The Inimitable Jeeves - P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Externalizing Queries in Mule Application</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/externalizing-queries-in-mule-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/externalizing-queries-in-mule-application/</guid>
      <description>I like to keep my code clean, understandable, and readable. It helps the next person who will take over my work. I try my best to avoid any trouble reading, maintaining, and updating the code. There are recommended and well known best practices about organizing Mule code. It involves better structuring of the project, maintaining configuration files, hiding or securing sensitive information like passwords and API keys, transaction management, or reconnection and caching strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking Water Habit</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</guid>
      <description>I discovered that the easiest way to start drinking more water is to always keep a water bottle with me. Before going to bed, I keep a bottle of water next to the bed. The idea is, when I wake up, the first thing I see is the water bottle. I drink that bottle before getting out of bed. This system helps me get a significant headstart in meeting my daily water drinking quota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Netcat to Debug Cloudhub Networking Issues</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/how-to-use-netcat-to-debug-cloudhub-networking-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/how-to-use-netcat-to-debug-cloudhub-networking-issues/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple trick I use to debug connection issues with the mule app deployed to CloudHub.
First of all its important to understand that there are different ways to set up your application
1. Using shared load balancer (i.e. cloudhub.io domain) with HTTP protocol.
In this scenario, the client application makes a request to a shared load balancer URL using HTTP protocol. The SLB forwards the request to the upstream mule application listening on port 8081.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap of 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>The end of the year is the time to pause, look back, and think about how the year went by. I am very grateful and fortunate to had an opportunity to enjoy a reasonably good time in 2020.
On the personal front
 We visited our families in India in January. I enjoyed meeting my parents, brother, in-laws, and friends. I did not travel for work and got more time to spend with my wife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Intermittent Fasting Saved My Life</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for 2020 was to stick to an intermittent fasting routine. I completed 6600 hours of fasting in 2020. On average, that&amp;rsquo;s 18 hours of fasting every day, for 365 days. Other interesting stats include the longest streak of 440 fasts and the longest fast of 37 hours. I did reasonably well to maintain a healthy weight despite stress-induced binge eating during the pandemic.
My fasting journey started in mid of 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Attachments to Salesforce Using MuleSoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/upload-attachments-to-salesforce-using-mulesoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/upload-attachments-to-salesforce-using-mulesoft/</guid>
      <description>This question comes up occasionally in my conversations with customers. Often there is a need to programmatically upload an attachment (a pdf or an image) file to Salesforce using MuleSoft. If the integration developer is not very familiar with the Salesforce Platform, it usually confusing due to the way Salesforce manages the attachments.
As shown in the following ER diagram, there are multiple entities involved in storing and managing the attachments in Salesforce erDiagram ContentDocument ||--|{ ContentDocumentLink : has ContentDocument { string Id string Title string PathOnClient date CreatedDate } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| Account : linkedEntity ContentDocumentLink { string Id reference LinkedEntityId reference ContentDocumentId picklist ShareType picklist Visibility } Account { string Id string AccountNumber } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| Contact : linkedEntity Contact { string Id string FirstName string LastName } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| sObject : linkedEntity sObject { string Id string SomeProperty }  Things to note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made to Stick and the Curse of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/made-to-stick-and-the-curse-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/made-to-stick-and-the-curse-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>I recently read &amp;ldquo;Made to Stick&amp;rdquo; by Chip Heath and Dan Heath. It was a fun and quick read. While I liked their framework of SUCCESs (Simple, Unexpected, Concrete, Credible, Emotional, Stories) to get the idea to stick, I thoroughly enjoyed the explanation of the Curse of Knowledge. The curse of knowledge occurs when a knowledgeable individual/expert assumes that the others have the background to understand a specific concept.
According to Chip and Dan, In general, getting your message across has two stages - the Answer Stage, and the Telling Others Stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/license/</guid>
      <description>This is a license file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MuleSoft Capacity Explanation for Noobs and CXOs </title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/mulesoft-capacity-explanation-for-noobs-and-cxos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/mulesoft-capacity-explanation-for-noobs-and-cxos/</guid>
      <description>I was talking to a C-level executive the other day and he asked me to explain how does MuleSoft&amp;rsquo;s capacity/sizing across various deployment models work. Given I always wear my technical hat I jumped right into the concept of cores and virtual cores and containers (and Kubernetes!) and did a pretty bad job. Fortunately, that executive was very accomodating and somewhat understood what I was talking about. Nevertheless, I should&amp;rsquo;ve done better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Spreadsheets and ArrayFormula for XIRR Calculation</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2017/google-spreadsheets-and-arrayformula-for-xirr-calculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2017/google-spreadsheets-and-arrayformula-for-xirr-calculation/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a simple way to calculate performance of my investments over time. Popular portfolio trackers like Moneycontrol and Value Research did not meet my needs. So I decided to try out Google Spreadsheets. Nice thing with Google Spreadsheets is its support for import and queries. e.g. AMFI India publishes daily NAV’s on their website http://portal.amfiindia.com/spages/NAV1.txt You can import the data programmatically and run a query on it to find desired NAV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Testing of Webmethods Services with REST Assured</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2017/automated-testing-of-webmethods-services-with-rest-assured/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2017/automated-testing-of-webmethods-services-with-rest-assured/</guid>
      <description>While testing REST APIs for one of my projects, I found REST Assured. It was perfect, as it took care of low level HTTP calls under the hood, and provided a high-level, easy to use framework to write tests. Not only REST Assured works really well to test webMethods flow services, you can also run these tests as part of Continuous Integration process through Gradle.
You will need following things on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Web Services Client adapter in Apama</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2016/using-web-services-client-adapter-in-apama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2016/using-web-services-client-adapter-in-apama/</guid>
      <description>Software AG Apama provides a SOAP-based Web Services Client adapter to invoke web services from your Apama application. In this post, we will see how to use this adapter in your application.
We will use a free web service available at CDYNE (link) for our application. This service has multiple operations, out of which we will use GetCityWeatherByZIP operation.
Below are the sample request and response messages for this operation, which we will use to describe our event definition in Apama.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Server Class Loading for Custom Jars</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2016/integration-server-class-loading-for-custom-jars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2016/integration-server-class-loading-for-custom-jars/</guid>
      <description>If a specific functionality is not available out of box from the integration server, you often need to use external jars or java libraries in IS. e.g. If you want to generate a PDF document or excel spreadsheet on your IS, you need to use your preferred libraries like IText or Apache POI.
It is not recommended to place your custom jars in the IntegrationServer/lib/jars folder. But Integration Server provides you couple of places to place these jars depending on how you want them to be loaded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
