<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Yogesh Dhimate</title>
    <link>https://www.dhimate.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Yogesh Dhimate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 19:36:24 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dhimate.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 19:36:24 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Career Profile  Software professional with 15+ years of global consulting experience in various roles as technical lead, integration architect and pre-sales engineer in the industry.
 Extensive experience in B2B and enterprise integration architecture using message oriented middleware, enterprise service bus, on premise/cloud implementation and API based solutions.
 Adept in analyzing information system needs, evaluating end-user requirements, and custom designing solutions for complex information systems architecture.
 Effective in work situations requiring an ability to manage concurrent projects and responsibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Spreadsheets and ArrayFormula for XIRR Calculation</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/blog/2017/google-spreadsheet-and-arrayformula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/blog/2017/google-spreadsheet-and-arrayformula/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a simple way to calculate performance of my investments over time. Popular portfolio trackers like Moneycontrol and Value Research did not meet my needs. So I decided to try out Google Spreadsheets. Nice thing with Google Spreadsheets is its support for import and queries. e.g. AMFI India publishes daily NAV’s on their website http://portal.amfiindia.com/spages/NAV1.txt You can import the data programmatically and run a query on it to find desired NAV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Testing of Webmethods Services with REST Assured</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/blog/2017/automated-testing-of-webmethods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/blog/2017/automated-testing-of-webmethods/</guid>
      <description>While testing REST APIs for one of my projects, I found REST Assured. It was perfect, as it took care of low level HTTP calls under the hood, and provided a high-level, easy to use framework to write tests. Not only REST Assured works really well to test webMethods flow services, you can also run these tests as part of Continuous Integration process through Gradle.
You will need following things on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>