<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Yogesh Dhimate</title><link>https://www.dhimate.com/categories/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Yogesh Dhimate</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhimate.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thinking in Bets</title><link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/thinking-in-bets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/thinking-in-bets/</guid><description>I recently read Thinking in Bets by Annie Duke. The book is about making better decisions when you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the facts.
Often times we confuse the quality of our decisions with the quality of the outcomes. Annie advocates that it is not the right approach. To make better decisions, it&amp;rsquo;s important to decouple the quality of decisions from the quality of outcomes. She talks about the hazards of resulting - the term poker players use to describe our tendancy of using outcomes to determine the quality of the decisions.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on Range by David Epstein</title><link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/reflections-on-range-by-david-epstein/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/reflections-on-range-by-david-epstein/</guid><description>I recently finished reading Range - Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World by David Epstein. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a new topic. It was recommended in Bill Gates&amp;rsquo; blog so I was curious about it and picked it up. The book talks about (hyper)specialization vs broad thinking in career as well as life. I had read one perspective about this in other books like &amp;lsquo;Talent is Overrated&amp;rsquo; by Geoffrey Colvin, and Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Made to Stick and the Curse of Knowledge</title><link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/made-to-stick-and-the-curse-of-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/made-to-stick-and-the-curse-of-knowledge/</guid><description>I recently read &amp;ldquo;Made to Stick&amp;rdquo; by Chip Heath and Dan Heath. It was a fun and quick read. While I liked their framework of SUCCESs (Simple, Unexpected, Concrete, Credible, Emotional, Stories) to get the idea to stick, I thoroughly enjoyed the explanation of the Curse of Knowledge. The curse of knowledge occurs when a knowledgeable individual/expert assumes that the others have the background to understand a specific concept.
According to Chip and Dan, In general, getting your message across has two stages - the Answer Stage, and the Telling Others Stage.</description></item></channel></rss>