<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Yogesh Dhimate</title>
    <link>https://www.dhimate.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Yogesh Dhimate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhimate.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Audible Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/my-audible-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/my-audible-experience/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last month I signed up for Audible. I thought it would be great to listen to the audiobooks, instead of reading them. In the past, I had enjoyed a few audiobooks on my long road trips. I especially remember listening to George Carlin’s books. The idea of listening to books on the go, the ultimate portability, and convenience, and an opportunity to give rest to my eyes was very enticing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate of Authenticity</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/certificate-of-authenticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/certificate-of-authenticity/</guid>
      <description>This week I got my new pair of glasses. I use photochromic lenses to help protect my eyes from the bright sunlight. These lenses turn dark when exposed to sunlight or high temperature. With this pair, my optician gave me a &amp;lsquo;Certificate of Authenticity&amp;rsquo; card from this company called &amp;lsquo;Transitions&amp;rsquo;. Transitions provide the photochromic feature in the lenses. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of them. Anyway, this certificate requested that I should register my purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Quick Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/february-quick-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/february-quick-update/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted anything in February. It was the busiest month I ever had. Our baby girl decided to arrive earlier than expected. Due to the pandemic, we decided to manage baby things on our own, without our parents. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, but for the first time parents like us, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. The most difficult part is baby can&amp;rsquo;t talk and exactly tell us what she wants yet. So we have to decipher her crying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking Water Habit</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</guid>
      <description>I discovered that the easiest way to start drinking more water is to always keep a water bottle with me. Before going to bed, I keep a bottle of water next to the bed. The idea is, when I wake up, the first thing I see is the water bottle. I drink that bottle before getting out of bed. This system helps me get a significant headstart in meeting my daily water drinking quota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap of 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>The end of the year is the time to pause, look back, and think about how the year went by. I am very grateful and fortunate to had an opportunity to enjoy a reasonably good time in 2020.
On the personal front
 We visited our families in India in January. I enjoyed meeting my parents, brother, in-laws, and friends. I did not travel for work and got more time to spend with my wife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Intermittent Fasting Saved My Life</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for 2020 was to stick to an intermittent fasting routine. I completed 6600 hours of fasting in 2020. On average, that&amp;rsquo;s 18 hours of fasting every day, for 365 days. Other interesting stats include the longest streak of 440 fasts and the longest fast of 37 hours. I did reasonably well to maintain a healthy weight despite stress-induced binge eating during the pandemic.
My fasting journey started in mid of 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
