<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Yogesh Dhimate</title><link>https://dhimate.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Yogesh Dhimate</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dhimate.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Drinking Water Habit</title><link>https://dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dhimate.com/2021/drinking-water-habit/</guid><description>I discovered that the easiest way to start drinking more water is to always keep a water bottle with me. Before going to bed, I keep a bottle of water next to the bed. The idea is, when I wake up, the first thing I see is the water bottle. I drink that bottle before getting out of bed. This system helps me get a significant headstart in meeting my daily water drinking quota.</description></item><item><title>Recap of 2020</title><link>https://dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dhimate.com/2020/recap-of-2020/</guid><description>The end of the year is the time to pause, look back, and think about how the year went by. I am very grateful and fortunate to had an opportunity to enjoy a reasonably good time in 2020.
On the personal front
We visited our families in India in January. I enjoyed meeting my parents, brother, in-laws, and friends. I did not travel for work and got more time to spend with my wife.</description></item><item><title>How Intermittent Fasting Saved My Life</title><link>https://dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dhimate.com/2020/how-intermittent-fasting-saved-my-life/</guid><description>One of my goals for 2020 was to stick to an intermittent fasting routine. I completed 6600 hours of fasting in 2020. On average, that&amp;rsquo;s 18 hours of fasting every day, for 365 days. Other interesting stats include the longest streak of 440 fasts and the longest fast of 37 hours. I did reasonably well to maintain a healthy weight despite stress-induced binge eating during the pandemic.
My fasting journey started in mid of 2019.</description></item></channel></rss>