<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MuleSoft on Yogesh Dhimate</title>
    <link>https://www.dhimate.com/tags/mulesoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MuleSoft on Yogesh Dhimate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhimate.com/tags/mulesoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upload Attachments to Salesforce Using MuleSoft</title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/upload-attachments-to-salesforce-using-mulesoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/upload-attachments-to-salesforce-using-mulesoft/</guid>
      <description>This question comes up occasionally in my conversations with customers. Often there is a need to programmatically upload an attachment (a pdf or an image) file to Salesforce using MuleSoft. If the integration developer is not very familiar with the Salesforce Platform, it usually confusing due to the way Salesforce manages the attachments.
As shown in the following ER diagram, there are multiple entities involved in storing and managing the attachments in Salesforce erDiagram ContentDocument ||--|{ ContentDocumentLink : has ContentDocument { string Id string Title string PathOnClient date CreatedDate } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| Account : linkedEntity ContentDocumentLink { string Id reference LinkedEntityId reference ContentDocumentId picklist ShareType picklist Visibility } Account { string Id string AccountNumber } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| Contact : linkedEntity Contact { string Id string FirstName string LastName } ContentDocumentLink ||--|| sObject : linkedEntity sObject { string Id string SomeProperty }  Things to note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MuleSoft Capacity Explanation for Noobs and CXOs </title>
      <link>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/mulesoft-capacity-explanation-for-noobs-and-cxos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dhimate.com/2020/mulesoft-capacity-explanation-for-noobs-and-cxos/</guid>
      <description>I was talking to a C-level executive the other day and he asked me to explain how does MuleSoft&amp;rsquo;s capacity/sizing across various deployment models work. Given I always wear my technical hat I jumped right into the concept of cores and virtual cores and containers (and Kubernetes!) and did a pretty bad job. Fortunately, that executive was very accomodating and somewhat understood what I was talking about. Nevertheless, I should&amp;rsquo;ve done better.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
